Christine Mulamba Lunda, MPH, MSW, LMSW

1530 East. McIver Road, Florence SC 29501 | (843)260-0844 | mulamba.lunda@gmail.com

Objective

Consistent and enthusiastic professional with more than 20 years in health care field and a strong work ethic with drive to success. Well versed in quality management and improvement processes. Brings program experience and skills to develop, motivate, lead and encourage employee productivity. Successful track record providing operational excellence; overseeing local, regional programs, training and overall quality improvement activities. Personal qualities of integrity, open mindedness and commitment to and passion for Community Based, Grassroots, Governmental and Non-governmental Organizations' mission and vision.

Education

University of South Carolina, Columbia, South Carolina

May 6, 2000

Arnold School of Public Health - August 11th 1997 – May 6th 2000

Master of Public Health - Concentration in Public Health Administration

College of Social Work - August 11th 1997-May 6th 2000

Master of Social Work- Concentration in Social Work Administration

Recipient of three year full-time scholarship for the Collaborative SC Public Health Social Work Project

Warren Wilson College, Asheville, NC

August 16 1993 – May 17, 1997

Bachelor of Arts in Social Work and Minor in Psychology

Post Graduate Licensures / Certifications

- Licensed Master of Social Worker (LMSW) since 6/19/2003
- Licensed Clinical Social Work (LCSW) candidate; completion December 2019

Centers for Disease Control (CDC) Institute for HIV Prevention Leadership

• Leadership and Achievement Certificate – *January – September 2006*

Francis Marion University

• Institute for Non-Profit Leadership *September 2008 – May 2009*)

Greater Florence Chamber of Commerce, Leadership Florence class of 2007)

Centers for Disease Control (CDC) and Prevention Certified Trainer / Coach, SC 2007 till present

One of 3 CDC certified trainers in South Carolina conducting annual, required ongoing regional based trainings at the request of South Carolina Department of Health and Environmental Control (SC DHEC)'s STD/HIV Division in the following areas related to behavioral health and HIV Prevention Counseling:

Guest lecturer – Coker College,

Hartsville SC, 2015 - till present

• Serve as substitute teacher as needed

Intern Field Instructor

• 12 years experience teaching social work students and help them meet their field internship goals and objectives with University of South Carolina, Coker and Limestone Colleges

Achievements and Honors

- Award of Excellence: for consistently demonstrating exemplary performance that goes above and beyond the standard call of duty. Presented by the South Carolina Public Health Association December 5th 2014
- Leadership Award *HopeHealth 2010*
- Unsung Hero in Our Communities' Fight Against HIV / AIDS (SC HIV/STD Conference 2006)
- Who's Who among students in American Universities and Colleges (*Warren Wilson College1995-1996*)
- Cross-Cultural Understanding Award (*Warren Wilson College May 16, 1997*)

Experience

Regional Director, Ryan White & Special Programs

Columbia, SC

Cooperative Health Center

May 2018- till present

- Project Director for HRSA's directly funded Ryan White Part C & D programs, providing guidance and leadership for the largest FQHC in the state
- Principal monitor for the Part D statewide initiative; Cooperative Health being the nucleus of the Part D program that centrally located in the Midlands of South Carolina
- Provides oversight for integrity of Ryan White programs at Cooperative Health as well as monitor 9 Part D sub--recipients which ultimate goal is to achieve the highest fulfillment of the HIV Care Continuum statewide by shifting the mindset so that HIV/AIDS is treated like any other chronic disease
- Conduct comprehensive campaigns with fellow FQHCs and community organizations; groups who are committed to serve the most underserved populations without judgement
- Oversee that FQHC's participate in a shared vision of being strategically located in health care shortage
 areas and providing healthcare services to disadvantaged populations; addressing stigma associated with
 our patient base and work tirelessly to break negative stereotype perceptions
- Coordinates with teams on the provision of comprehensive, quality, state of the art family centered HIV and primary care services to all HIV infected Women, Infants, Children, and Youth (WICY) living in the state of South Carolina. Special emphasis is given to the underserved and at-risk WICY living with HIV
- Coordinates with teams to strengthen the organizational infrastructure to support telehealth/telemedicine in an effort to increase access to quality family-centered care services for low-income, uninsured, underinsured, and underserved (WICY) populations living with HIV/AIDS in the state of South Carolina.

Regional Director of Grants Management, Quality Improvement and Training Florence, SC

HopeHealth, Inc (Federally Qualified Community Health Center)

Jan. 2015 – May 2018

Demonstrate results in managing through complex systems and negotiating win-win agreements. Develop, guide, provide expertise and oversight in the establishment, implementation, and evaluation of Quality Improvement activities regionally for Ryan White, Prevention, and Specialty Service sites. Monitor data management, Quality Management Plans, and adherence to In+Care Campaign guidelines, CDC guidelines, and Health Resources Services Administration (HRSA) guidelines. To establish training curriculums and protocols as it relates to Site needs/program needs, maintain training grid per position descriptions/roles and funding needs, monitor and promote training opportunities that engage teams and prepares them for completion of job duties/field expertise. Promote and Provide Education and Training Opportunities including onboarding / orientation of staff

- Advancement through a series of promotions, culminating in responsibility for providing oversight and program development for the largest HIV/AIDS program in the state of SC.
- Demonstrate continued leadership skills and knowledge managing multiple federally funded programs

- Responsible for multi-site (staff of 7 in Aiken, staff of 20 in Florence and staff of 16 in Orangeburg) Grants Management and Quality Improvement, Training activities
- Organizational Planning, development and evaluation of program activities
- State and regional trainer (one of 5) for (HIV / HCV testing and / or group level interventions) at the request of SC DHEC's STD/HIV Division; trained more than 450 individuals in the state (2007 present)
- Consultant for direct program staff in various program areas and other agencies
- Knowledge of state and federal grant rules / regulations
- Liaison to HRSA project officers (2007 2015)
- Serve on the organization Leadership / Management Team since 2004 and contribute to develop policies for organization and grant reporting, and writing.
- Chair of the HIVQUAL Ryan White Part C Grantee Meeting in collaboration with the South Carolina Primary Care Association and National Quality Center
- Conference presenter: National Ryan White Conference, Washington, DC and at HIV/STD and Viral Hepatitis Conference, Columbia SC
- HIV Planning Council member since 2006, served as chair on Prevention Committee for 5 different terms

Special Project: Subject / Content Expert

Lusaka, Zambia (Africa)

American International Health Alliance, HIV/AIDS Twinning Center

March 2016 – March 2017

Selected as a content expert on project with University of South Carolina (USC) that was selected as the resource partner in the twinning partnership with Chreso Ministries (in Zambia) to strengthen the capacity of their healthcare workers to mitigate the impact of HIV/AIDS on key populations.

- Provided technical expertise and experience, commitment to and demonstrated success in addressing
 issues related to key populations sensitivity trainings that were provided a strong foundation for a
 successful partnership experience
- Assisted in fostering productive working relationship that supported Chreso Ministries in building the capacity of Zambia's healthcare workers to provide HIV services to key populations

Project Director: Substance Abuse Mental Health and Services Administration (SAMHSA) Targeted Capacity Expansion (TCE) Project Sept. 2014 – Oct. 2017

• Strong project management skills managing complex, multifaceted projects resulting in measureable successes and program growth. Provided direction for the TCE project over 3 year grant cycle overseeing budget of 1.5 million including 4 sub-recipients; project that expanded substance abuse treatment and HIV services for African American, Hispanic/Latina, and other racial/ethnic minority women (ages 18 years and older), including heterosexual, lesbian, bisexual, previously incarcerated women, and their significant others, who have substance use or co-occurring substance use and mental disorders and are living with or at risk for HIV/AIDS. Liaison to SAMHSA TCE project officer

Produced evaluation report at the end of the 3 year project period and worked with sub-recipients to implement continuous quality improvement activities at each respective location

- Increased awareness of HIV/HCV and related risk factors among minority women and other residents in the community; Program staff served 5,433 clients for substance use disorders in Year 2 and Year 3
- Increased number of minority women and other residents in the community who received HIV and HCV testing and who know their HIV/HCV status; Program staff tested 2,649 individuals for HCV in the target

area. Increased number of minority women and other residents who had testing positive are linked to services and engaged in care;

• Developed a community partner organization collaboration network for HIV/HCV care with 40 providers
☐ Increased number staff and community partners trained to facilitate evidence-based interventions.

Director of Program Services

Florence, SC

HopeHealth, Inc (Federally Qualified Community Health Center)

Oct. 2005 – Jan. 2015

Developed and implemented strategies that maximize the synergies among multisite and multi-program in organization, regionally and externally facing role managing relationships in the community. Experience on team management and development, and establishing standards of performance across all programs. Cultivated existing relationships with community partners with the goal of ensuring sufficient space and resources, as well as access to services. Developed and used existing clinical report card and program dashboard; established consistent, objective program performance standards of accountability. Excellent verbal and written communication skills with exceptional attention to details.

- Developed and implemented a system to evaluate the skill, experience and professional development needs of staff
- Implemented a professional development program to address employee experience and skill gaps
- Work with staff to develop / implement objective performance measurements across sites, to ensure consistent, high quality evaluation and goal setting and evaluate outcomes
- Instilled a sense of accountability among team members by modeling tight oversight of individual and organization performance standards
- Strength in hiring, recruiting, managing, development, coaching and retaining individuals and teams empowering them to elevate their levels of responsibility, span of control and performance
- Provided oversight / supervision for Health Resources Services Administration (HRSA) and SC DHEC grants for Ryan White Parts B and C HIV programs: implementation, monitoring, quality management, evaluation grant writing and reporting
- Responsible for monitoring and managing a 3 million dollar budget more than 10 years
- Grants management: key liaison responding to federal and state project officers for numerous grants
- Participate in community and statewide committees, sometimes serving in role as consultant
- State and regional trainer for SC DHEC since 2007. Supervision of a staff of 15 staff in the infectious disease department
- Deep understanding of employee performance improvement counseling plans and corrective action policies
- Multiple presentations conducted at local, state, national and international level on topics including CQI
- Develop, revise and implement effective written policies; Oversee the volunteer / internship program

Prevention Services Coordinator

Florence, SC

HopeHealth, Inc (AIDS Service Organization)

Aug. 2004 – July 2005

Management team member with proficiency in implementation of quality improvement process and work plans, knowledge managing reporting tools and experience working with information to develop and implement program evaluation systems. Demonstrated success developing and evaluating program models and selecting successfully operationalizing innovative programs.

- Lead Principal Investigator on 6 year CDC funded project; implementation, monitoring and supervision
- Developed a prevention program that met or exceeded expectations

- Responsible for supervising 10 and interns of prevention program staff; submission of reports for program and conduct direct services to clients in a clinical setting as well as in the community
- Oversaw implementation of all prevention programs and provide ongoing monitoring of prevention deliverables and program requirements
- Prepared reports (in collaboration with prevention team) for submission to Centers for Disease Control
 (CDC) and Department of Health and Environmental Control (DHEC)
- Developed and maintain Prevention Program Policies and Procedures Manual
- Skilled at working with different reporting systems
- Developed quality assurance plans for prevention programs and arrange in-services and trainings for prevention staff
- Coordinated internal team meetings (multidisciplinary team, Outreach team and Ryan White teams)

Public Health Social Worker / Supervisor-Social Work Programs

July 2002-Aug. 2004

South Carolina Department of Health and Environmental Control (SC DHEC

Kingstree – SC

Responsible for overall health communication activity in order to promote positive health outcomes and wellness. Teaching people about behaviors that promote wellness. Conduct psychosocial assessments and develop / monitor treatment plans. Encourage learning opportunities for individuals to make healthy decisions. Link clients to community resources. Use appropriate strategies and methods to facilitate health promotion and disease prevention. Understand diverse populations and follow public health social work code of ethics. Good communication and documentation skills. Home visitation with clients focusing on the individual and environment. Provided crisis intervention as needed

- Helped clients cope with challenges faced in their lives
- Provided clinical social work services and therapy to diagnose and then treat individuals who have mental, behavioral, and emotional disorders
- Assure maintenance of case files and other records in strict compliance with policy, regulation and procedure
- Actively participate in ongoing training as needed to meet all certification standards and credentialing policies; Communicate with inter-disciplinary teams and process evaluation activities

Public Health Social Worker - Maternal and Child Health Program

June 2000-June 2002

South Carolina Department of Health and Environmental Control (SC DHEC

Greenville. SC

Develop, monitor and assess health communication intervention and policies. Improved the lives of people who are in need of support and help including visits in the hospitals and homes. Assess psychosocial needs of individuals, groups, families with high and/or low risk health conditions as well as persons in crisis

- Implement and manage health education strategies, intervention and programs
- Assess patient and client needs for health education, psychosocial needs including change readiness
- Develop, identify, implement and improve patient education materials and other tools that encourage healthy decisions
- Supervise Public Health Assistants directing, developing and disbursing plans of care
- Generate and coordinate disbursement of social work related referrals coming in from other departments
 .e.g. nursing, outreach, environmental health, family planning doctors' offices, community agencies;
 maintained caseload between 70-80 clients and conducted home visits. Update client charts including
 doctors' orders, progress notes and billing information
- Develop and implement time limited treatment goals and objectives; documentation done based on agency standards

Conduct educational groups for Young Teen Parent Program through agency collaboration

Graduate Research Assistant

Jan. 1999-May 2000

South Carolina AIDS Training Network

University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC

- Participated in planning for statewide 1999 HIV/STD conference
- Assisted with day to day office tasks on HIV related topics and/or issues as assigned
- Assisted in compiling Perinatal HIV prevention manual utilized by clinicians and physicians
- Assisted supervisor on quality improvement projects

Graduate Research Assistant

Aug. 1998-June 2000

Institute for Families in Society

University of South Carolina, Columbia, SC

- Assisted in conducting process evaluation for program development and implementation strategies focusing on resource development and maintenance of community partnerships
- Participated in grant-writing efforts to develop and/or sustain community partnerships
- Conducting literature searches on program evaluation for community based initiatives
- Established and monitored data collection systems including. tracking forms
- Presenter: International Conference, Kingston Jamaica
- Revised and updated school-based resource manual utilized as guide for home, community and schools

REFERENCES UPON REQUEST